

Adeline Chu Ling Ling

No. 76, Taman Kalien, No.2/ 1C Lorong Sungai Tapang 7th Mile 93250 Kuching, Sarawak Malavsia. Date of Birth: 29th October, 1979

Nationality: Malaysian I.C. No.: 791029-13-5384 Contact no.: +6016 8663100

Objective Statement:

To acquire a challenging career with a solid Multi-national company (MNC), utilizing the opportunity to offer proven and developing skills within the company.

Brief Profile:

More than ten years of working experience with accounting & administrative skills, purchasing, sales & marketing.

Special abilities :

Multi-tasking talent, prioritize and deliver results, ability to communicate with different types of people, multi-cultural awareness, willing to learn, strong work ethic and the ability to work well within a team environment, fluent in English, Bahasa Melayu, Mandarin and other Chinese dialects (i.e. Hakka, Hokkien, Teochew and Cantonese.)

Computer knowledge:

MS Office (Words, Power Point, Excel & Outlook), Internet, Mac OS, SAP Accounting Software & UBS Accounting Software.

Education:

Bachelor Degree in International Business from InterAmerican University, USA. Accounting Cert, KBI,Kuching SPM Grade 2, SMK Batu Lintang

Training(s):

Festo Didactic course – Introduction to Pneumatics

Employment History

GRP Sdn. Bhd.

Executive, Sales (Adhesives & sealants)

March 2013 - Present

Reporting to head of dept. / general manager, visit potential customers for new business, provide customers with quotations, identify new market and business, gather market and customer information and provide feedback on buying trends

Pansar Co. Sdn. Bhd.

Sales Executive (Building Products)
May 2011 – January 2013

Duties: Responsible for promoting and selling company's range of products to building and construction industries, build strong relationship with existing customers to encourage continuous usage of company's product, provide quotation and follow up sales with customers. Provide customer service which includes regular visit to their office as well as their project sites.

Kui Heng Enterprises Co.

Sales & Marketing Executive (Industrial/ Oil & Gas spare parts)
May 2008 – May 2011

Duties: Responsible for the company's Sales & Marketing activities include identifying and securing new customers, project market studies and building strong rapport with customers with the objective of instilling customers' loyalty for the company, to attend enquiries and prepare quotation for clients and thereafter to follow up on quotations submitted.

Sara-Ed Trading Sdn Bhd

Project Executive
July 2005 – June 2007

Duties: Responsible for co-ordinating and preparing of tender bidding clarifications and documentation during tender bidding stage according to the project requirement. In-charged of goods sourcing (both local & international), price negotiation, design product catalogue for assigned projects, mark-up & quote pricing, prepare project costing for assigned projects, & coordinated shipments

PU Engineering Sdn Bhd

Assistant Secretary
January 2005 – May 2005

Duties: Type correspondences, tender documents, reports for allocated projects, control all Quality Management System documents and record related to ISO implementation, ensure all endorsed MOA/ documents are registered and kept in safe place, filing of incoming and outgoing correspondences after action been taken by relevant parties, communicate with engineers the whereabouts and on action taken for incoming mails marked to them

Employment History (continue)

Kim Hin Industry Berhad

Account Assistant
June 2000 – January 2005

Duties: Maintained and updated computerized GLD, assigned correct account codes to each accounts, check the correctness of daily posting, preparation of monthly bank reconciliation statements, daily preparation of journal vouchers, prepare monthly printouts of trial balance and check for accuracy, preparation of monthly Sales Tax & Service Tax, performed other duties which were assigned from time to time.

Hock Seng Lee Berhad

Clerk (Accounts Department) April 1998 – April 2000

Duties: Assignment of accounting codes and casting of data, daily preparation of payment & journal vouchers, preparation of monthly bank reconciliation statements, reconciliation of creditors' balance to statement of accounts, filing of documents

Referees: Referees available upon request.